Ethan Perez

956-357-7283 | ethan@ethanperez.com | linkedin.com/in/ethanperez | github.com/ethanperez

Summary

Product-focused engineer with 9 years of experience shipping across the full stack. Experience as a VC-backed startup co-founder, team lead and manager, and senior IC at scale-ups through IPO.

Relevant Skills

Languages: TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, SQL (Postgres), Kotlin, HTML/CSS

Frameworks: React, React Native, Node.js / Deno, Next.js, Fastify, Apollo GQL, AWS (Lambda, EC2/Fargate, SQS)

EXPERIENCE

Tally Labs

New York, NY

Co-founder, CTO

Apr. 2022 - Present

- Built and launched a creator licensing platform using Next.js and PostgreSQL that matched 4,000+ collectors and generated \$1.4MM in primary revenue, then raised \$12MM in seed funding from a16z crypto
- Launched Avenue, a generative AI mobile app for interactive story telling on iOS and Android using React Native to 44,000+ unique users
- Developed LLM orchestration and prompt engineering for text and image generation pipelines, using a GraphQL Fastify API on AWS (Fargate, Lambda, and SQS) to serve dynamic content from OpenAI, Anthropic, and Flux
- Designed and deployed an on-chain protocol for interactive narrative experiences using Deno and Fly.io VMs, enabling revenue-sharing across creators, contributors, and participants. Also built a flow-based web interface for non-technical authors to create branching narrative logic and test in real time.
- Prototyped and launched 10+ products, using direct user feedback to guide iteration and product direction
- Hired, managed, and mentored a remote team of 6 engineers, balancing technical leadership with execution

Peloton New York, NY

Engineering Manager, Android Mobile and TV

Sep. 2021 - Apr. 2022

- Led a 12-person cross-functional team of Android engineers and QA to deliver bi-weekly releases, partnering with PMs and cross-team stakeholders to drive alignment across Android platform and architecture groups
- Increased Android app feature parity with iOS from 50% to 90% within one year by prioritizing high-impact feature gaps while balancing new product development alongside parity work
- Established scalable release and development workflows with GitHub and custom Slack integrations to support a multi-team Android codebase during a framework migration to reduce deployment friction

Senior Software Engineer

Jul. 2020 - Sep. 2021 Jun. 2018 - Jul. 2020

Software Engineer

- Developed and launched Android Mobile and Fire TV applications in React Native to 100,000+ users
 Led launch preparation, testing, and hardening for Poloton class streaming React web application; previous
- Led launch preparation, testing, and hardening for Peloton class streaming React web application; previously classes were only available on iOS and proprietary hardware
- \bullet Planned and led migration of Android and Fire TV apps to native Kotlin, improving startup time by 60% (4s) and integrating with Peloton's Android monorepo
- Rewrote Android Mobile and TV video streaming experience in Kotlin as a part of app performance migration and consolidated video analytics across all Android devices, reducing streaming errors by 40%
- Introduced RUM observability for Web content using New Relic, enabling real-time alerting and simpler debugging

DraftKings

Boston, MA

Senior Software Engineer

Jan. 2018 - Jun. 2018

Software Engineer

Jun. 2016 - Jan. 2018

- Built new Draft Experience as a greenfield React app, improving maintainability while reducing load time by 20%
- Led migration of email service provider in a .NET microservice, lowering costs and improving reliability
- Developed universal navigation system in React, Redux, and ES6 used across the DraftKings ecosystem

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology

OMSCS

Master of Science, Computer Science

Aug. 2017 - Dec. 2020

The University of Texas at Austin

Austin, TX

Bachelor of Business Administration, Honors and Management Information Systems

Aug. 2012 - May 2016